[Music]
hello everybody it is nicole from
kiwi and today we'll be reviewing the
new gen craft squash set that was kindly
gifted to me
so let's not waste any time and hop
right into the video on the gen crafts
website
it is originally 60 dollars but is on
sale for 27.97
and on amazon it is on sale for 27.97
as well
for the packaging the gouache comes in a
cardboard box with the colors listed on
the back
as well as inside inside the set of 50
there are five plastic trays with 10
tubes in each tray
the colors that are included are yellow
and pink
red and purple blues and teals
green and browns and grays
each tube is non-toxic and individually
labeled
with the name and code at the top there
are 12 milliliters in each tube
and the paint tubes are sealed and in
order to open them up
you have to turn the cap around to poke
a hole with the pointy tip inside
the pan itself is kind of a jelly
consistency
when it's out of the tube and i only
added a little bit of water to get the
paint moving when i started the swatches
gouache can be watered down like
watercolors but it can also be used
straight out of the tube like an acrylic
i found when swatching the colors that
some of the colors are more opaque
and some are more sheer and i'll cover a
little bit more about this in the pros
and cons
the paint's dry with a matte finish and
it feels almost chalk like when you
touch it
now i wanted to test how the gouache
would look out of the tube
versus watered down since you can use it
both ways
for this example i used the color red
and
straight out of the tube the color is
very opaque and very pigmented
i added a bit of water for every step i
went down
to change the transparency and to show
the range of color
of course you can make so many more
colors with this and i didn't do the
best job
in making a even gradation but hopefully
this quick test was still able to show
you that this one color can have a range
of different
shades
i also wanted to test out if the gouache
paint would be opaque
after layering it on top of a dried
gouache layer
i did two tests for this one with the
same colors on the top and bottom
i wanted to use these six rainbow colors
to give a kind of a range
of both warm and cool tone as well as
light and dark colors
so for the top test i added white
straight out of the tube
on top of the rainbow colors to see if
it would go on opaque
or if it would still be sheer and for
the bottom
i did the same except i used the color
black
and ultimately what the test shows is
that the white is not really opaque on
any of the colors
one layer is pretty sheer and more
layers make it slightly more opaque
but it's not a solid white and you can
still see the brush strokes
however the black is super opaque and
covers the color entirely
especially when it's not watered down
and there aren't any visible brush
strokes
now before getting into the pros and
cons i want to note that gouache is
definitely not my medium of choice
i worked with it before but it's
definitely a challenging
medium for me and i tend to use it more
like watercolors
i also base these pros and cons on my
painting style and workflow
but you may find that some of the pros
and cons are interchangeable depending
on how you like to work
so with that being said for the pros
there is a large variety of colors
included
and i like that the tubes are named and
numbered because it makes it easy to
identify
when you're trying to find the certain
color especially if you're
looking on your swatch card i like that
gouache kind of comes with the option of
using it either opaquely or watered down
so you kind of are getting
two in one and the gouache definitely
dries a lot quicker than watercolors
and for someone that is impatient like
me i do
like that aspect but there are
definitely cons to this which leads me
into
my cons so as i just mentioned
drying quickly can also be a con because
when i was coloring this piece
i found that the paint dried too quickly
and it made the paint
appear not as smooth as i would like it
to be
this is most visible in the background
when i was trying to cover a large area
and i found that it just kept leaving
brush strokes or
streakiness that i normally wouldn't get
in watercolor
i actually did this piece twice because
the first time
i tried it where it was more opaque like
an acrylic
and that didn't really work so the
second time i tried it more watered down
like a watercolor and it still didn't
provide a smooth finish
like i prefer another con is that some
of the colors are more opaque than
others
for example when i was adding the yellow
sparkles on top of the dark teal
background
it didn't really appear as opaque as i
would like
the tubes are also quite small and
there's not really a lot of paint inside
and i found that some tubes were more
full of air than others
so when i would try and dispense
the paint it kind of puffed with air and
then i
deflated my tube of course i don't think
that's intentional and it may just be
on random ones because some were more
full than others
and the last con is that fine liners
don't work
on top of the gouache because of the
matte finish that the gouache leaves
after it dries
however i did find that brush pens work
so if you plan on using brush pens then
it should be fine
but fineliners i found didn't even leave
a mark
so overall if you're someone that does
rough sketch painting
and likes a painterly look with layering
and brush strokes
then this might be something for you to
try out
but to be completely honest i personally
did not enjoy using these because the
gouache dried too quickly for me
and my paint style or my style in
general
is that i like things to be smooth and
blended
however do keep in mind that i do not
use gouache often
so i'm definitely not an expert and
maybe i wasn't using it right
but i've used the winsor and newton
gouache before and it's definitely not
the same quality
so i don't recommend this brand to
professionals
and i feel like this medium is just
really challenging to work with
in general and definitely has a learning
curve
so it's ultimately up to you if you want
to give it a go and
see if you can do it better than i did
i'll be sure to leave
links to some of the gouache youtube
videos that i referenced
so you can see if you want to try out
gouache in the first place
and have an interest in it but either
way i hope you found this video
useful or helpful if you enjoyed the
video and want to see more videos like
this
be sure to hit that subscribe button and
ring the bell so you're notified of when
i post a new video
so with that i want to thank you all so
much for joining me today
keep drawing keep creating and i'll see
you all next time
bye
[Music]